<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-13T01:07:14-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/feed.xml</id><title type="html">rence.</title><subtitle>a collection of thoughts by Lawrence Wang</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 2019" /><published>2019-12-31T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-31T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/2019/">&lt;p&gt;The 2010s was the first full decade I’ve lived through, the first through which I tracked every single movie I watched, the first during which I started making bimonthly playlists. It’s also when I got my first personal computer, when I created my first enter-the-name-of-every-single-social-media-platform account, and when I initiated first contact with the internet, games, music, movies — essentially the beginning of my life as a screenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life had been completely revolutionized in the 10s: I started the decade wandering around Disneyland Paris without knowing a single word of French; one second I was preparing for my middle school entrance exam in Wuhan, the next I was sitting in a classroom speaking broken English in a suburban school in California; I ended the decade with no knowledge of Spanish other than a damned 4 on the AP Spanish test. I regretted not going to The 1989 World Tour; I sang along to Team without knowing any other song from &lt;em&gt;Pure Heroine&lt;/em&gt; which would become the love of my life; I hated &lt;em&gt;Bloom&lt;/em&gt;, then liked &lt;em&gt;Bloom&lt;/em&gt;; I hated Sam Smith, then loved him, then hated him again for not singing the title track on his tour; I wiggled my way around art, though never finding out exactly what I love; I moved from imagining to making, from collecting floor plans to not having time to collect floor plans, from reading Chinese books to reading English books back to reading Chinese books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, when &lt;em&gt;Frozen&lt;/em&gt; first came out, I must’ve seen that movie at least 10 times because every single teacher would play it at school when they had nothing else for us to do. Let It Go became a cultural phenomenon, and Elsa was my favorite animated character until &lt;em&gt;Zootopia&lt;/em&gt; came about. This year, I went to see &lt;em&gt;Frozen II&lt;/em&gt;, it doesn’t have the same magical quality of the first one, of course. But something about it calms my wandering heart that has never been more lost and alone and scared of growing old. I can pursue the unknown even from within the safety of the castle, and someday, I will realize that &lt;em&gt;I am the one I’ve been waiting for, all of my life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010s was fiery youth, incorruptible happiness, kaleidoscopic colors. It was dying in L.A., seeking directions and adapting to the lack thereof, and learning we are not what we thought we were. What was done, what was said — maybe it was a whole lot of baggage. But I also believe that if we find any way to a wild heart, one foot in front of another, and stay ‘til the A.M., god &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; save our youngblood. Because, after all, being on top of the world, acting stupid for fun, living wild and free, that’s the way it’s supposed to be, no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I will play Long Live at exactly 23:58:57 so that I step into the new decade with “the start of an age.”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Next decade, do the next right thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;也許世界就這樣&lt;br /&gt;
我也還在路上&lt;br /&gt;
新的十年，迎接星辰日出，再见孤独&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Short" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">The 2010s was the first full decade I’ve lived through, the first through which I tracked every single movie I watched, the first during which I started making bimonthly playlists. It’s also when I got my first personal computer, when I created my first enter-the-name-of-every-single-social-media-platform account, and when I initiated first contact with the internet, games, music, movies — essentially the beginning of my life as a screenager.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/the2019.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lover: The Evolution of Taylor Swift</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/lover/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lover&amp;#58; The Evolution of Taylor Swift" /><published>2019-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/lover</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/lover/">&lt;p&gt;We all remember the vengeful spirit of Taylor Swift. From claiming that “there’s nothing I do better than revenge” to “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,” a certain part of her discography was dedicated to feuds and lost loves. Just two years ago, Taylor can be seen burning bridges and throwing shades, (in addition to being &lt;em&gt;presumably dead&lt;/em&gt;) in the music video for “Look What You Made Me Do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;reputation&lt;/em&gt; were a product of the venom and frustration that consumed her in the aftermaths of the Kim-Kanye controversy, then &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; is the complete antithesis of that. With her newest release, Taylor delivers her most stylistically diverse and artistically complete body of work yet, featuring poignant introspection, playful maturity, and most importantly, a grand forgiveness, for both her enemies and herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the outcome of the drama, the existence of this album is proof of Taylor taking confident strides away from the days of bitter blame games. Realizing that contentions only feed into the bloodthirsty, clickbaity headline culture of today, Taylor also concludes that there are more important issues in life, such as the health of family members (“Soon You’ll Get Better”), political advocacy (“The Man”), and finding the one true love (“Lover”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-past-in-the-past&quot;&gt;A Past in the Past&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2006, Taylor Swift debuted as a country princess. She was heralded as “America’s Sweetheart,” that curly-haired girl next door who sang about love stories and fairytales. To be fair, it was fine for the 17-years-old Taylor to be petty, to sing about failed relationships and shitty boyfriends. But it did become problematic when people, including herself, seemed to forget that sweethearts grow up too, just like prom queens do not stay young forever and memories someday fade. When she gradually became complacent with an immaturity that resorted to triviality and revenge, it felt like a stagnancy in her creative direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The halos also meant heightened expectation from fans and critics alike. During the release for &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, both Swift and her music were recognized as perfection in the Pop universe. She had the flawless image, soaring sales numbers, all-star team of friends, and an award-winning album. Yet while she has reaped the benefits of media exposure, she also suffered — because public perception is an odd thing - the same people that crowned you can turn against you just as quickly. In today’s &lt;em&gt;stan-or-cancelled&lt;/em&gt; culture, the perfection demanded by the public can be exhausting. According to a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/taylor-swift-rolling-stone-interview-880794/&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with The Rolling Stone, Taylor stated that “[people] decided in 2016 that absolutely everything about me was wrong. If I did something good, it was for the wrong reasons. If I did something brave, I didn’t do it correctly. If I stood up for myself, I was throwing a tantrum. And so I found myself in this endless mockery echo chamber.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/lover2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-beginning&quot;&gt;A New Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some bizarre way, however, her fall from grace also prompted the evolution of her artistry. Her once-teenager audience are now adults, and it seemed appropriate for her to grow out of the expectations and halos that once chained her. She did lose her perfect image, but in the death of her reputation, she became aware of the delicacy of herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Archer” is Taylor’s attempt to face that delicate part of her. The drum beats build a looming anxiety that lasts for the entirety of the track, creating an anticipation for climax, yet never reaching a cathartic moment. By depicting the uncertainty inherent to love, the song also reminds us that uncertainty is simply a fact of life, that things often do not have definitive ends, that somethings just become forgotten, trail off, and reach nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that achingly sad moment of introspection, Taylor becomes aware of her shattered self as the veneers peeled away — she realizes that anyone can see right through her, just as she sings “I see right through me.” As the weariness finally washes over, the desperation for someone to stick around this time highlights precisely how there is no guarantee of it. After half a decade of jumping from romances, she understands that love stories are not as simple as “baby just say yes.” They may be complicated, messy, and inconclusive. Fairytales do not exist in real life, and if you want something, you have to fight for it — whether it be truth, vindication, or love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-grand-forgiveness&quot;&gt;A Grand Forgiveness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the lesson &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; brings is knowing ourselves. Understanding our own fragility makes us more accepting of others. Understanding our own defects makes us braver and more honest. “I Forgot That You Existed,” with playful and light presentation, contrasts greatly against the dark, gothic tracks from reputation. “It’s Nice To Have A Friend,” is the other side to “This Is Why We Can’t Have Nice Things.” Through a celebration of love and passion, she has learned to forgive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As dramas of the past dissipate, as the happy, the unhappy, the fortunate, and the unfortunate fade, Taylor Swift, in the spirit of moving on, bathes in “Daylight” and proclaims that “I wanna be defined by the things that I love. Not the things I hate. Not the things I’m afraid of, or the things that haunt me in the middle of the night.” She cannot remain America’s Sweetheart forever. Nobody can. Just like Rihanna’s modeling career and Gaga’s makeup line, there comes a time for Taylor to find her own voice. This time around, Taylor Swift announces that she will not be defined by resentment or snake emojis. Instead, she would like to be remembered by forgiveness, self-care, and maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone makes mistakes. We can all be seized by vengeance and rage. But more importantly, we also grow up, encounter ourselves, and find the things that matter more. Leaving the bad in the past — that is the victor’s attitude. Being defined by what you love — that is &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">We all remember the vengeful spirit of Taylor Swift. From claiming that “there’s nothing I do better than revenge” to “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,” a certain part of her discography was dedicated to feuds and lost loves. Just two years ago, Taylor can be seen burning bridges and throwing shades, (in addition to being presumably dead) in the music video for “Look What You Made Me Do.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/lover1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Eighteen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/18/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eighteen" /><published>2019-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/18</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/18/">&lt;p&gt;18 would be a tie-dyed kaleidoscope of colors in my imagination: I would run around the neighborhood like I promise myself everyday (&lt;em&gt;and watch one less YouTube video&lt;/em&gt;). I would be driving around town ordering iced coffee at 1 A.M. (&lt;em&gt;because I would’ve gotten my DL before my permit expired&lt;/em&gt;). I would be getting ice cream at Venice, having spontaneous road trips, or visiting the Broad. I would actually have a senior quote (&lt;em&gt;thanks Troy High School&lt;/em&gt;), actually understand Chemistry, actually not care about school, and actually magically get a 5 on AP Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be fearless, free-spirited, and stupid-for-fun. I would’ve found my wild. Days would be drowning in screaming colors, nights would be shrouded in slow murmurs of the Pacific Ocean splashing on Huntington Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, none of that happened. In retrospect, perhaps some of my hopes were unrealistic, strange, and unapologetically absurd. But then again, who said the me at 17 didn’t deserve to dream?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess reality is like water: it would never be as lively or rapid or possess the same relentless vigor as the waterfall of dreams. And like a river flows, time washes away the sharp edges, the deep yearnings, and the grand ambitions of dreams, until all its uniqueness and individuality are seemingly dulled by mediocrity and compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now what? In light of the inevitable fall of dreams, end of youth, withering of all that’s bright and beautiful, are we to become senseless faceless inadmissible degenerates? Are we to be forever lost in the previous version of ourselves that is forever banished to the prison confining all supposedly immature wishes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still don’t own a record player. I still walk from school to Starbucks (&lt;em&gt;which apparently is like the most un-senior thing ever&lt;/em&gt;). I still sleep way too late and am way too serious about finding &lt;em&gt;the one&lt;/em&gt; (yogurt). My life is still not like &lt;em&gt;Love Simon&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;To All the Boys&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;The 100&lt;/em&gt;. I still feel so listless and empty after finishing every Chinese drama. I still haven’t gotten the letter in the mail that would pronounce me the Prince of Demark (&lt;em&gt;did you not know that?&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But none of that discounts the fact that I can find interesting things in the most banal tasks, and seek pleasure in the most desperate situations (&lt;em&gt;like my non-sensical conversation with Martha during the AP Spanish test, during which I’m sure neither of us understood each other!&lt;/em&gt;). I’ll find solace in empathy, thankfulness, understanding, and the belief that my terrible test grades in Stats are actually simply due to luck and not due to the pseudo-mathematics nature of statistics (&lt;em&gt;nor my inability to math in general&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s fair, I guess, to an extent. Not everything in life will be glittering mesmerizing breathtaking spectacles. Life is composed of little parentheses of losing and winning. We don’t get to win all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, our world may be absurd, Meursault may be correct, Jake may never find the passion he desires, Estragon may remain forever waiting, there may never be an answer to the metaphysically posed yet historically diametrically answered question of the elusive meaning of existence, because, after all, once a week is quite enough to dine with one’s own relations, and the truth is rarely pure and never simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ll keep dreaming, keep counting stars like I’m 3, keep embracing the bigger wows, even though I might not be wiser now. ‘Cause I mean, who’ll be there to stop me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, maybe my 18 will remain kaleidoscopically colored, forever.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">18 would be a tie-dyed kaleidoscope of colors in my imagination: I would run around the neighborhood like I promise myself everyday (and watch one less YouTube video). I would be driving around town ordering iced coffee at 1 A.M. (because I would’ve gotten my DL before my permit expired). I would be getting ice cream at Venice, having spontaneous road trips, or visiting the Broad. I would actually have a senior quote (thanks Troy High School), actually understand Chemistry, actually not care about school, and actually magically get a 5 on AP Spanish.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/eighteen.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">1989: It’s a Harry Styles Thing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/1989/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1989&amp;#58; It's a Harry Styles Thing" /><published>2019-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/1989</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/1989/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; was the album that took 2014 like storm. It’s known as a lot of things: the transformational work that marked the emergence of a pop queen from a country princess; the singer-songwriter’s comeback project to sweep all the award shows; the album that beat &lt;em&gt;To Pimp a Butterfly&lt;/em&gt; to Album of The Year at the 58th Grammy Awards; &lt;em&gt;you get the idea&lt;/em&gt;. But what intrigued me the most is how the album had &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harry Styles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; so blatantly written across its lyrical content and thematic presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taylor Swift has never had a shortage of boy friends: whether it be Joe Jonas, or John Mayer, or Tom Hiddleston. Concurrently, it’s never been rare for Swift to write about them: whether it be We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together, or Dear John, and Getaway Car, respectively. But in &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, Taylor documents her journey through love with a desolate determination, charming sweetness, and keen introspection. Taken together, the subject matter of every song— from New York City in Welcome to New York to London in Clean— chronicle the ups and downs in Swift and Styles’ relationship and narrate a most beautiful love story from beginning to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://hips.hearstapps.com/cosmouk.cdnds.net/14/37/nrm_1410270679-taylor-swift-harry-styles-hasnt-dated-rolling-stone-interview-cosmopolitan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-perfectly-styled-fantasy-story&quot;&gt;The Perfectly Styled Fantasy Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they first started dating in the winter of 2012, they seemed like the perfect couple. One Direction was the international phenomenon, Taylor Swift was America’s Sweetheart: both talented, both paragons of their respective sexes, both with impressive fan bases. Both living in NYC— topic of the album’s first song. Some might call it the worst New York anthem ever, but I think it may very well be a celebration of the historic decision to move to NYC that allowed this love affair to develop, and in that sense, introduction to the bittersweet romance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third track, Style has the most obvious connection to Harry. First, &lt;em&gt;the title&lt;/em&gt;. Second, the references, such as the “long hair, slicked back, white t-shirt” and the “James Dean daydream look in your eyes.” Third, Taylor said it herself in an interview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s basically one of those relationships that’s always a bit off. The two people are trying to forget each other. So, it’s like, “All right, I heard you went off with her,” and well, I’ve done that, too. My previous albums have also been sort of like, “I was right, you were wrong, you did this, it made me feel like this”—a righteous sense of right and wrong in a relationship. What happens when you grow up is you realize the rules in a relationship are very blurred and that it gets very complicated very quickly, and there’s not a case of who was right or who was wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship, according to Taylor, has never been a smooth ride. There’s been rumors of Harry Styles hooking up with other girls (which is semi-corroborated by herself). There’s been the thoughts of “Are we out of the woods yet? Are we in the clear yet?” in Out Of The Woods, the most vivid rendition of their love story on the album. We gain glimpses into their life together: the polaroid taken on their couch, the two paper airplane necklaces, the snowmobile accident during the skiing trip, the stitches and tears in the hospital room… All told with immense underlying emotion and, more importantly, bursting apprehension wondering whether the woods are just trees, where the next roadblock would be, how long this precious story would last, when it would end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In I Wish You Would, the two have broken up, but the regret is eating both of their minds alive. Taylor has allegedly said that the song is about her ex who “bought a house literally one road adjacent to hers.” In Perfect, Harry mirrors Taylor’s lines: “windows down, you pass my street, the memories start” with “and if you like midnight driving with the windows down.” The story goes that every night, he would drive home, accidentally turn into her street, because he wanted to tell her how “he just wants to stop by her house and see her,” but he never did— because he thought she hated him now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, what he didn’t know is that she also stayed up watching his headlights pass by her windowpane, that “she’s still in love with him.” All the while he’s deciding whether to turn up at her house at 2 A.M., she’s hoping that he would. Turn right back around. Know that she’d never forget him. Know that she misses him too much to be mad at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, that imperfect love is savored in Wildest Dream, in which Taylor wishes her lost love would see her in his dreams, and remember her the way he would remember him. No longer the vengeful spirit found in Better Than Revenge, Taylor’s first thoughts when entering a relationship are “when this ends, I hope it ends well. I hope you remember me well.” With imagery of the ocean and a maritime journey, This Love continues the reminiscence of the good times and the bad, as she relives moments of the love that left a permanent mark on her. As the sonic repetition of “this love” glide past our ears, we begin to feel those memories of love appearing and disappearing, but never leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything comes to a halt in Clean. Drafting dramatic metaphors of drought, the song symbolizes the absence of a relationship that once took up the artist’s entire world. For months all she could do was think about the good times. For months the memories haunted her. Until one day, all of a sudden, she realizes she’s been in London for two weeks and hasn’t thought about him. She’s fine, and she hopes he’s fine. In the pouring rain, the first thought that came to her mind was “I’m finally clean.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.vice.com/noisey/content-images/article/taylor-swift-1989-world-tour-review-essay/Screen-Shot-2015-07-13-at-11-40-25-AM.jpg?crop=1xw:0.9736752717391305xh;center,center&amp;amp;resize=1200:*&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-selling-coming-of-age-story&quot;&gt;The Best-Selling Coming-of-Age Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the story. Style outlines a timeless image. Out Of The Woods highlights a directionless anxiety. All You Had To Do Was Stay is the cheerful-tunes-shrouded melancholy of wanting it all back. How You Get The Girl is the instruction manual she wished he had followed to get her back. I Wish You Would conveys regret. This Love recounts the times that seem so beautiful in retrospect, and in Clean — it’s all gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, they did not end up together. I never cared much about their relationship before, but after listening to the album knowing the Harry Styles undertones and hints, I can’t help but imagine what might have happened if the two did end up together. What if they held onto each other and cherished each other? In interviews, members of One Direction were always making fun of Harry about Taylor. Weren’t they Perfect for each other? Weren’t they meant for each other? Weren’t they supposed to never go out of Style and always be each other’s Wildest Dreams?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the audience, all we could ever do is listen to what artists have to say. We will never get the full picture. We will never know how beautiful the love was, how intense the fall out was, how acute the heartache was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what we do know is that &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; exemplifies the artist’s transformation from the girl sitting on bleachers, looking out the window to the boy next door, believing in fairy tales — to a woman understanding that not every romance will end like a fairy tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an album about Harry Styles. It is an album to tell one story. Maybe it’s the love story of one fatalistic relationship. But more importantly, it’s a coming of age story of Taylor Swift. She realizes that not every relationship will have a knight in shining armor. She realizes fairy-tale endings are not a given, they are not how love is supposed to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think the way I used to approach relationships was very idealistic,” she says. “I used to go into them thinking, ‘Maybe this is the one — we’ll get married and have a family, this could be forever.’ Whereas now I go in thinking, ‘How long do we have on the clock — before something comes along and puts a wrench in it, or your publicist calls and says this isn’t a good idea?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/3584/3437428988_efb401a079_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-real-love-story&quot;&gt;The Real Love Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real love stories are not just the sassiness “she wears short skirts I wear T-shirts” or playfulness in “I can make a bad guy good for a weekend,” or the vengefulness in “she underestimated just who she was stealing from.” Love is more than seeing that single face in every crowd, and breakup is more than pointing fingers. It can be messy, difficult, painful. The lines are blurred. The right and wrong are mingled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; is more than a best-selling pop album, it tells the story of growth, of maturing, of self-discovery. Of a princess finding her prince charming but without a happily-ever-after. In her sophomore album Fearless, Taylor Swift used one chart-topping single to characterize an endearing love story. With &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, it took her an entire album to do so. It’s a love story without “baby just say yes,” but it is more empowering, more precious, and more real, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real love story is bittersweet, not nearly as dreamy as Love Story. But it’s more lively and contains much more strength. It comes with the realizations that love is not one-size-fits-all, that there might never be a happily-ever-after, and that resolutions might never exist. The anxiety might be overwhelming; the heartbreak might be unbearable. That’s what real love takes. That’s what make us believe that the imperfections in the fact that “I’m just a guy you’ll write breakup songs about” make the “red lips, little skirt, long hair, white t-shirt” style truly perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some information are excerpted from Tumblr.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><summary type="html">1989 was the album that took 2014 like storm. It’s known as a lot of things: the transformational work that marked the emergence of a pop queen from a country princess; the singer-songwriter’s comeback project to sweep all the award shows; the album that beat To Pimp a Butterfly to Album of The Year at the 58th Grammy Awards; you get the idea. But what intrigued me the most is how the album had Harry Styles so blatantly written across its lyrical content and thematic presentation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/TS1989.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Russian Doll: It’s Hard to Stay Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/russian-doll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Russian Doll&amp;#58; It's Hard to Stay Alive" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/russian-doll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/russian-doll/">&lt;p&gt;You would think that after an entire school year of Nietzsche, Meursault, Godot, Kafka, Hemingway, and &lt;em&gt;Like Water for Chocolate&lt;/em&gt; in International Baccalaureate English would be enough absurdist discussion for a while, if not an entire lifetime. But &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt;, the extremely odd, extremely beautiful, and extremely thought-provoking delight, proved to be just that piece of existentialism I never knew I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer brilliance in the editing and cinematography is just the least of it: the message is what I find to be the most interesting. Particularly, the message that “it’s too easy to die that it’s hard to stay alive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series is deeply absurd, with the protagonist running into death in the most unexpected, dark-humor ways — at times, it’s nearly the real life version of Dumb Ways To Die. It’s also deeply existential, with a beautifully-crafted dialogue on which parts of the numerous ways to die actually convey the essence of life. It’s a story about two equally unfortunate people finding their own meaning of existence, and somehow that’s incredibly grand and moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nadias-dilemma&quot;&gt;Nadia’s Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time passes by linearly throughout the show, but the main character, Nadia, is stuck on the night of her birthday party — the recycled moments of her waking up in front of the bathroom mirror is a diametric symbol of death and rebirth. Nadia and the other protagonist, Alan, theorized that the seemingly eternal time-loop is a punishment for their mistakes during their childhood. Nadia wanted to leave her mother, and attributed her mother’s death to her own fault, after which she decided to push other people away to avoid any possibility of genuine connection that might end up hurting both parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But through the eyes of Ruth, Nadia’s life-long friend and mentor, it was never Nadia’s fault. She was a tiny seed buried in darkness fighting her way to the light. She wanted to &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt;, and “it’s the most beautiful thing in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ruth speaks arguably the most touching line of the series: “Do you still have that in you? I look at you now, chasing down death at every corner. Sweetheart, where is that gorgeous piece of you pushing to be a part of this world?” Nadia tears up, as would anyone who has felt the powerlessness of barely living, day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nadia is not a completely good person. Sometimes she’s not kind enough, or proactive enough, or friendly enough — she knows that about herself, so while she’s unforgiving of everything around her, that cynical attitude also extends to herself. She would appear tough, nonchalant, totally untouchable, absolutely inconsiderate, the consequences of which include a deep feeling of isolation and emptiness that can not be cured by the alcohol, or random sexual encounters, or an israeli-joint-highlighted birthday party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that’s her defense mechanism, of closing herself off from the world, thus eliminating the possibility of getting hurt and hurting other people. Or perhaps that’s who we all are — &lt;em&gt;incompletely good&lt;/em&gt; — as a result of our tendency to avoid pain and discomfort. But may I suggest to you that the experiences of bruising, the pain inherent to love, hate, and betrayal are the most real, human things, and that when we insulate ourselves from the world, we lose parts of what make us human in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/RD2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-is-not-the-end&quot;&gt;It Is Not The End&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ending is a beautiful moment. It has a quality that is as promising as &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt;, but not quite &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt;. The two protagonists reappear in front of their bathroom mirrors one last time and realize they are in different dimensions — the other person is back in cycle #1 and has no recollection of the death-defying adventures they shared together. Now, they have to look for the other person and convince them that all those hundreds of attempts at living and dying were actually real. As the screen splits in half, the audience witnesses a hopeful Alan assisting the turbulent Nadia, and a patient Nadia comforting the confused Alan. And as they walk through the winter New York streets, the two screens merge into one, with a renewed Nadia holding a torch, finally, again, pushing to be a part of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the mediocrity of daily chores and the pressures from expectations can make life feel like hell, like purgatory on earth. Sometimes, the anxiety of being alive strikes blows to us that seem impossible to handle. But as &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt; reminds us, &lt;strong&gt;we are not alone in this world&lt;/strong&gt;. We still have each other, can find each other, and save each other. Just like in the ending when Nadia and Alan march, joining Horse’s parade of monsters, passing the shoulders of their alternative selves — &lt;em&gt;they have not given up on each other&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world out there can be a vile one. A lonely one. A troubled one. One in which it’s hard to stay alive. But if we can all dig into our hearts, see ourselves for who we are, and learn to forgive and reconcile, maybe we can also let go of the cold, exoskeletal shells of protective covers; let go of the habit of keeping people at a distance; let go of the need to hide our insecurities and conceal our mistakes. In doing so, perhaps we might rediscover the fine world that is worth fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May this newfound hope and companionship in &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt; mean that the past moments of “I just want to die” are not the end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Television" /><category term="Netflix" /><category term="TV" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">You would think that after an entire school year of Nietzsche, Meursault, Godot, Kafka, Hemingway, and Like Water for Chocolate in International Baccalaureate English would be enough absurdist discussion for a while, if not an entire lifetime. But Russian Doll, the extremely odd, extremely beautiful, and extremely thought-provoking delight, proved to be just that piece of existentialism I never knew I needed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/RD1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Commencement Address: Lessons I Learned</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/graduation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Commencement Address&amp;#58; Lessons I Learned" /><published>2019-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/graduation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/graduation/">&lt;p&gt;Ladies and gentlemen, teachers, administrators, Class of 2019:  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Good evening. It is an absolute honor to be here. Six years ago, when I arrived in America, quite literally “fresh off the boat,” I never imagined I would be standing here. When I first stepped foot on Troy’s campus, I was entirely clueless about my future. Now, standing here at graduation, I know exactly the direction I’m going in life! Just kidding, I’m just as clueless as freshman year, but I do know that my experiences at Troy will serve as the foundation of whatever I decide to do in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past 4 years have been enlightening to say the least. I personally cannot count how many Spanish presentations I made (well at least now I know 15 is quince and not diecicinco), I learned that sometimes diamonds are produced from the pressures of procrastination, and who would’ve thought that the difficult times at Troy might actually bring people together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I figured, since we’ve all seen the once clueless freshmen mature into aspiring models, journalists, entrepreneurs, and engineers, (oh and did I forget doctors?), since we’ve all witnessed how our eye bags grow exponentially on the daily during the college app season, and we’ve all heard about how we are “the worst case of senioritis” Mr. Rod has ever seen; so today, I would like to share some lessons I learned through the journey of high school with my fellow classmates, because it’s 2019 and sharing is caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First lesson is that you are what you love, and who loves you, but not who doesn’t love you. As a first generation immigrant, I used to be extremely self-conscious: of my appearance, of my slight accent (and my inability to English in general— to this day), and of anything that seemed mildly un-American. But through Troy, I learned that really, it doesn’t matter all that much. We all make mistakes and have our deficiencies, and that’s ok. A part of life is mastering the art of losing, losing the perfect image, losing that A+ in Fundamentals of Computer Science, and, most importantly, losing snapchat streaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the contemporary poet and metaphysician Taylor Swift once said, we shouldn’t care so much if we feel misunderstood by a lot of people who don’t know us, as long as we feel understood by the people who do know us, who will show up for us, who see us as human beings. Sometimes I think it’s fearless to say goodbye to a situation that’s exhausting or toxic, and oftentimes, by leaving things behind and being yourself, you will find much broader horizons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second lesson is to build yourself up strong but humble. Surround yourself with positivity and support. Know that criticism doesn’t have to defeat you: it can strengthen you instead. We’re all different, and although it might not seem easy to get past the things we don’t always understand, remember that it is absolutely possible. And when you’re under attack, just think that the people who carry such negativity often have rather tragic lives themselves. So next time, pity them instead. Nobody is perfect, but humility always goes a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, personally, that when Harvard University intimately tells us that they regret to inform us, or when Mr. Kim puts in that 0% on the acid-base titration Iodine Clock test, or when the all-nighter to cram the entire novel &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; is no longer sustainable even with multiple cups of coffee, it can seem like the end of the world. But I also know that rejections are natural to the human experience, and that in the long, long marathon of life, obstacles will show up every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t ever let those obstacles sidetrack you, because it may be a fight to live an interesting life, but it’s a fight worth fighting for. Because if we are brave enough to chase after our ideals with unwavering determination, then there is a chance that we’ll succeed. Because I know that someday, when we get to where we’re going, the stories we write will be worth telling, and retelling, and listening to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t become discouraged when the suffocating reality comes crashing down. Sometimes dreams are broken to make space for new ones. They represent a direction, but they’re not always the destination. Perhaps we don’t grow toward them, or for them. We grow to exceed them. Maybe we’re not quite ready for them today, but I know we’ll be ready &lt;em&gt;someday&lt;/em&gt;. If we don’t get there, we’ll get &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt;. And I hope that the belief in someday, the dream of somewhere, will be our solace in midst of the ceaseless cluelessness of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for all the memories, Class of 2019, I am so glad to have had all of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delivered May 31, 2019 at Troy High School’s Commencement Ceremony as valedictorian for the Class of 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Featured" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">Ladies and gentlemen, teachers, administrators, Class of 2019: Good evening. It is an absolute honor to be here. Six years ago, when I arrived in America, quite literally “fresh off the boat,” I never imagined I would be standing here. When I first stepped foot on Troy’s campus, I was entirely clueless about my future. Now, standing here at graduation, I know exactly the direction I’m going in life! Just kidding, I’m just as clueless as freshman year, but I do know that my experiences at Troy will serve as the foundation of whatever I decide to do in the future.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/graduation.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">To the Class of 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/the-end/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To the Class of 2019" /><published>2019-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/the-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/the-end/">&lt;p&gt;Dear Classmates,  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There won’t be another time when we get to dress up like nuns with our gowns, or jump up and down like insane, or throw our caps in the air and mess up the world - it’s what graduation means. A part of it inevitably means giving up some of the immaturity and innocence that characterized the teenage. &lt;em&gt;But may I suggest to you&lt;/em&gt; that we should not concede everything to the process of growing up. We can still be crazy, original, true to ourselves. The most distinguishing part of our individuality can never be lost or ceded. And I hope that someday, when we look back, we will know that we never strayed from our true path.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Remember that to be honest, what I liked, were the things I didn’t know. And that when it rains it pours, so stay thirsty like before. As Drake once said: “I guess you lose some and win some, long as the outcome’s income. I want it all, and then some.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I want it all, and so should you.&lt;br /&gt;
Try to shine. Stay wild, C/O 2019.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yours,
Lawrence&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Short" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">Dear Classmates, There won’t be another time when we get to dress up like nuns with our gowns, or jump up and down like insane, or throw our caps in the air and mess up the world - it’s what graduation means. A part of it inevitably means giving up some of the immaturity and innocence that characterized the teenage. But may I suggest to you that we should not concede everything to the process of growing up. We can still be crazy, original, true to ourselves. The most distinguishing part of our individuality can never be lost or ceded. And I hope that someday, when we look back, we will know that we never strayed from our true path. Remember that to be honest, what I liked, were the things I didn’t know. And that when it rains it pours, so stay thirsty like before. As Drake once said: “I guess you lose some and win some, long as the outcome’s income. I want it all, and then some. I want it all, and so should you. Try to shine. Stay wild, C/O 2019. Yours, Lawrence</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/classmates.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Last Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/last-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Last Day" /><published>2019-05-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/last-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/last-day/">&lt;p&gt;So that was the long-awaited last day of high school, in the blazing California sun, per usual. Nothing seemed out of place, other than the makeup AP Spanish Test, and the chromebook that still needs to be turned in. Everything exactly the same as the Troy High School I’ve experienced for infinite afternoons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I remember after all these years at Troy? The tree that looks like a thumbs up? The yearly field fertilization that stinks from 50 miles away? The carpet in the halls that’s now gone? The new warrior statue in the quad? The needles that fall from the pines in the winter? The sky that was especially blue one day, or the dusk that was particularly colorful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people walking on the gym roof during AP testing. The unplanned mis-fire alarms. The Mr. Heaton burning bridges in classroom and the Ms. Oropeza not putting in the final exam. The printing Philo papers franctically in Falleta. The technical difficulties during rallies. The walking through the entire Elf Dance floor because “I can’t find my partner.” The Shmooping &lt;em&gt;Catcher&lt;/em&gt; in one night. The rolling chairs in Teresa Mormont, or the large tables in Gregory Platt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ditching ROTC. The coding bats. The Spanish projects. The existentialism. The us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memory really is a funny thing. It will be liquified as time passes it by, blurring the details and leaving merely an outline of the emotions and the values attached to it. And then we would have to use our imagination to fill in the things that will be gone forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We lived. Crazily. Fanatically. Dogmatically. Uniquely. Hedonistically. We lived like that for four years, jumping and dancing, looking stupid just for the heck of it. Maybe it’s only the courage of youth, the beginner’s luck that allowed us to do so. Yet I can’t stop wondering what luck must it be, to meet the most sparkly people, in my most free years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that’s really the most beautiful story. It might not be a fairy tale, with godmothers and pumpkins and unconditional romance. It might be composed of way too many midnight decisions, lonely feelings, 1 A.M. desperate texting for homework, and tantrums on classroom floors. But it’s beautiful nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost like the end of a grand orchestral performance. We came from different places, and we once again part our own ways and resume our directions in life. Saying goodbye has been difficult, precisely stemming from the overwhelmingly irreplaceable charm of the rollercoaster ride. But to me, these beautiful memories will be worth framing in albums incorruptible by time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">So that was the long-awaited last day of high school, in the blazing California sun, per usual. Nothing seemed out of place, other than the makeup AP Spanish Test, and the chromebook that still needs to be turned in. Everything exactly the same as the Troy High School I’ve experienced for infinite afternoons.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/lastday.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">La La Land: A Not-So-Happily Ever After</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/la-la-land/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="La La Land&amp;#58; A Not-So-Happily Ever After" /><published>2018-11-15T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/la-la-land</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/la-la-land/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is charming like nothing else: the sentimental music, the fanciful images, the idealistic story— everything is  romantically mesmerizing. Chazelle’s previous work, &lt;em&gt;Whiplash&lt;/em&gt;, was similarly impressive. But &lt;em&gt;Whiplash&lt;/em&gt; was angry, hysterical, dangerous, saturated with sweat, tear, blood, and a risky devotion, whereas &lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is clear, transparent, with a dreamy magnificence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easily one of the best films of 2016, but the imperfect ending makes many wonder if it vibed with the holidays and Valentines season. However, may I suggest that it is precisely the imperfection that makes this story of lovers and dreamers real, precious, and unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is charming like nothing else: the sentimental music, the fanciful images, the idealistic story — everything is  romantically mesmerizing. Chazelle’s previous work, &lt;em&gt;Whiplash&lt;/em&gt;, was similarly impressive. But &lt;em&gt;Whiplash&lt;/em&gt; was angry, hysterical, dangerous, saturated with sweat, tear, blood, and a risky devotion, whereas &lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is clear, transparent, with a dreamy magnificence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easily one of the best films of 2016, but the imperfect ending makes many wonder if it vibed with the holidays and Valentines season. However, may I suggest that it is precisely the imperfection that makes this story of lovers and dreamers real, precious, and unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;love-and-dreams&quot;&gt;Love and Dreams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, Sebastian and Mia were never meant for each other. In life’s lowest points, love and friendship might be better described as the desperate need for someone to whom one can vent the pessimism and from whom one might extract encouragement - and that was the case for Mia and Sebastian. They saw their failures, their unrecognized efforts, their dreams in each other, and they mistook the commonality in their misfortune as love, expressed through words of comfort for their unrealistic hopes. It sounds romantic on paper, but not so pretty in practice. They would argue about minute details, which is not unusual for couples, but when they fail to adapt to each other’s values and expectations, is it realisitc for them to manage living together for the rest of their lives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy utter the words “I love you,” but loving takes much more than a three-syllable phrase. To love is to take the responsibility of your actions and to accept the weaknesses in yourself and your partner. We can’t all be perfect, but similarly, we can’t always live in such grand self-consolation, where we tell ourselves we’re in love but really we’re just selfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mia is selfish. She’s had a successful, rich boyfriend whom she dumped. So why did she choose Sebastian? It’s because she sees herself in him: the dejected dream chaser. In reality, however, she was never going to give up everything for him. When Sebastian was slowly becoming the musician he’s always wanted to be, she wanted him to admit that he wasn’t happy. But Sebastian does love music, and who said he didn’t love touring? Mia felt imbalanced: when the dreams they associated with each other came true, they suddenly couldn’t bear each other anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the dream that unites them is precisely what separates them. Sebastian thought he found the love of his life, but it’s nothing more than in a particular place, at a particular time, he met someone who needed someone. In the end, they both loved their dreams more than they loved love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/LLL1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dream-of-stars&quot;&gt;The Dream of Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe, neither of them needed a happily-ever-after. LA has boundless deserts, but at the end of those deserts, there’s the splendor of the city and the equally boundless sea. When the blue ocean embraces the blue sky, it’s just like idealists embracing the ephemeral joy, even if thunderclouds might descend the very next second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countless dreamers, like Mia, come to Hollywood in search of their aspirations. Countless dreams are shattered here. Yet for as long as there’s people young and old, searching, looking, the stars will never dim, and everything will always be ever so glorious. This city of star is the lovely night under the purplish nightfall, the pier shrouded by the brilliant dawn, the dinner club with a piano lit by the dim lamp light. It’s where music never stops. It’s a dreamland where all the colors are bright, pure, where even the air seems intoxicated with sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does such a charming world exist? We all know the answer to that. The road to dreams is difficult, with steep and rocky inclines, with thorns and spikes and prickles. The city of star doesn’t shine for anyone in particular. The people who realize their dreams are few, yet who can say, with confidence, that those who try are fools?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-high-road&quot;&gt;The High Road&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dreams are the constant variables in everyone’s life. Some change, some are given up, but some have been kept all along. At the end of the film, the two met in the jazz club, both clutching their dreams. When their eyes met, both watery, were they not smiling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is also nowhere near a tragedy. After all, Sebastian and Mia held on to their aspirations. Both became what they wanted to be. Both conquered the unthinkable future of the once discouraged dreamers. Both lived exactly as they imagined 5 years ago: the girl now a renowned star, the guy now owning a jazz club — not many can afford such luxury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the love, it forged both of their lives. Intentionally or not, they have affected each other’s decision at an important junction. The two came together on the way to their dreams, and one pushed the other to success. Both of their dreams came true at the cost of losing each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, they both found that someone in the crowd, whom they’ve waited for, whom they needed to know. After they’ve lifted each other off the ground, they went on to continue their lives. They might not have been ready to wholeheartedly love each other, but they did wholeheartedly need each other, help each other, and succeed &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; each other. And as such, despite the regrets and what-ifs, who can say that a not-happily ever after is not splendid as well?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Movie" /><category term="La La Land" /><category term="Musical" /><category term="Dream" /><category term="Movie" /><summary type="html">La La Land is charming like nothing else: the sentimental music, the fanciful images, the idealistic story— everything is romantically mesmerizing. Chazelle’s previous work, Whiplash, was similarly impressive. But Whiplash was angry, hysterical, dangerous, saturated with sweat, tear, blood, and a risky devotion, whereas La La Land is clear, transparent, with a dreamy magnificence.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/LLL2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Reputation: A Career-Ending Flop?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/reputation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reputation&amp;#58; A Career-Ending Flop?" /><published>2018-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/reputation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/reputation/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; was the biggest album of 2018. There’s absolutely no doubt in that. It is also the best selling album of 2017. There’s no doubt in that either. But ever since its release, the media and others have criticized it as being Swift’s biggest flop in her career. But is it really? The simple answer is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. But if we dive deeper into the undercurrents, perhaps we would see the essence of the album more clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-drama&quot;&gt;The Drama&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast backward three years, the release of &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;phenomenal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It was heralded as the most iconic, textbook example pop record of the 21st century. Through the sound and delivery, Swift created a world that mixes the vintage and modern, that’s both nostalgic and energetic. A world that places love, and more importantly, the courage to love, on a towering pedestal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the aftermath of the 1989 era was not pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the summer of 2016 unraveled, Swift’s “American Sweetheart” image shattered. Overnight, the media’s perception of her turned from the relatable country princess turned pop queen to a nasty snake suffering from victimhood complex. From Kanye West’s “Famous” (and its music video) to Kim Kardashian’s rapid fire attacks to the god awful breakup with Calvin Harris for songwriting credit claims to the rebound of Tom Hiddleston that lasted a total of 3 seconds, Swift’s reputation suffered and plummeted and crashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The friends she once had, or partied with, or went on the Victoria’s Secret runway with, or made music videos with turned against her. The media that once adored and supported her slandered her. The innocently misled public again showed their viciousness and flooded her social media with the snake emoji. And although it’s impossible for us outsiders to know what really happened underneath the drama, it’s undeniable that the happenstances of that summer seriously affected Swift and fueled the creation of this album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://seatgeek.com/tba/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/taylor-swift_promo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-album&quot;&gt;The Album&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, she took a one year break from releasing material, which was unprecedented to say the least and severely hampered her systematic release schedule. But then came &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt;, an introspective saga about the aftermath of the collapse of a pop queen’s impeccable reputation— the entire album feels more like Swift’s journey of making peace with the taint in her public image than a traditional love-pop album or diss album. She starts her journey with no sense of remorse whatsoever in I Did Something Bad and Don’t Blame Me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But if he drops my name, then I owe him nothin’ &lt;br /&gt;
And if he spends my change, then he had it comin’ &lt;br /&gt;
Don’t blame me, love made me crazy  &lt;br /&gt;
If it doesn’t, you ain’t doin’ it right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But gradually, that strength she feigns and desire for vengeance seems to fade away, as she scores a new love, a love that is delicate and pure, yet unbreakable by the rumors and defamation. The mid-album songs, such as Gorgeous, King of My Heart, and Dancing With Our Hands Tied, give off a 1989-ish sentiment regarding love, although presented with choppier and darker songwriting. Towards the end of the album, time and love together have been able to heal the scars left behind by the smearing criticisms. In This Is Why We Can’t Have Nice Things, Swift makes snarky remarks that point at specific people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Friends don’t try to trick you&lt;br /&gt;
Get you on the phone and mind-twist you &lt;br /&gt;
But I’m not the only friend you’ve lost lately&lt;br /&gt;
If only you weren’t so shady&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through joking about the agony and injury of the past, she proves that she has grown, that she is indeed beyond the drama, that she has let it go like clouds blown away by the winter wind. Call It What You Want is the final statement that marks the attitude of the Reputation era. Her castle of friends that she used to fortify herself against her insecurities crumbled. Her unpreparedness in the fight forecasted her defeat. She lost her crown, yet in the end, she found something greater. She lost her impeccable reputation, but that’s alright, because she’s stronger now, and the media can really just call it what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sonically speaking, the album mixes elements that are indeed new to Taylor Swift albums, with a greater emphasis on electronic and hip-hop influences. Lyrically speaking, the album is as strong as ever, and Getaway Car is the prime example of that. The entire song tells such a vivid and convincing story of a love that was doomed to fail since its conception. The contrasting colors create an ominous atmosphere while the couplets forge a rhyme scheme that strongly aligns with the beat. The lines easily morph into visuals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Well, he was runnin’ after us, I was screamin’, “Go, go, go!” &lt;br /&gt;
But with three of us, honey, it’s a sideshow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And my personal favorite part comes with the bridge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m in a getaway car  &lt;br /&gt;
I left you in a motel bar &lt;br /&gt;
Put the money in a bag and I stole the keys &lt;br /&gt;
That was the last time you ever saw me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She leaves him with no regret. Takes the money and the keys.  Just like how she rode in the car, cried in the car, flew in the car, now she’ll leave in the car. With a light push on the gas pedal and she’s gone, leaving the dusts dancing behind the getaway car. The story is fateful, and brutally honest, the exact same brand of honesty in storytelling that serves as the hallmark of all her songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first half of the album, Swift discusses reputation and dreams of revenge in tracks shrouded with a dark, industrial voltage. Yet in the second half, she continues the iconic vibe of 1989 that pushes the passion of love to momentous heights. She climbed up the ruins of her wounded reputation, and then found salvation in love— that’s a concept that everyone can relate to. Thus, the listening experience is the audience’s journey, along with Swift, to find the exit to the pain and the gleaming sun of a newfound comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.philly.com/resizer/aDjqN0LW_l-NmG96oVQuPCcpjX8=/1400x0/center/middle/arc-anglerfish-arc2-prod-pmn.s3.amazonaws.com/public/T45JUACWFNFHJLT23COTJZ3K6M.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Section&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-verdict&quot;&gt;The Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of success, &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; was a gigantic commercial success. In a world with streaming dominating the scene, Taylor Swift is one of the few artists that can sell a million copies in the first week. Aside from sales, the Reputation Stadium Tour grossed 345.7 million dollars, which is 100 million more than the 1989 World Tour with 50% less shows. &lt;em&gt;Also making it the &lt;strong&gt;second highest&lt;/strong&gt; per show gross in the history of concert tours&lt;/em&gt;. The production of the tour doubtlessly makes it the best of 2018, with marvelous performances from eras old and new, incredible choreography, and stunning stage design and fireworks. Without essentially any promotion, the fact that Reputation accomplished all of the above is absolutely phenomenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; is an unmissable album from 2017, and I was rather speechless when it wasn’t nominated for Album of the Year at the 2019 Grammys, especially since it’s the first year of expanded nominations. In fact, similar to &lt;em&gt;Speak Now&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; did not receive any General Field nominations, and like &lt;em&gt;Red&lt;/em&gt;, it did not win a single Grammy. This might mean that &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; is a flop according to Swift’s standards, or at least, the Old Taylor’s standards. I mean, remember how she went on to make &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; to slap the Recording Academy in the face after her defeat with &lt;em&gt;Red&lt;/em&gt;? But then again, the Old Taylor is dead, and perhaps she is simply tired of the massive routine promotional effort behind a Grammy run. With 10 Grammys in her pocket and gracefully marching into her late 20s, maybe what we are seeing is, in addition to a sincere reflection of a lost prestige, a growth and maturity signifying that she’s unbothered by cosmetics like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, looking at the other nominees this year in the General Field, we are seeing a growing dominance of hip-hop. Whether this is due to the rise of streaming platforms or the Recording Academy’s attempt at “inclusivity,” it’s undeniable that hip-hop is becoming the new “pop.” No matter how some dislike the new sound, or how the promotion is lacking, it’s hard to deny that &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; is a successful pop record that totally deserves to be nominated, and entries like End Game and Delicate totally merit a nomination and even the award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps &lt;em&gt;Reputation’s&lt;/em&gt; “flop” is a portrayal of a larger phenomenon: the decline of pop as a genre. A phenomenon that started with The Chainsmokers’ Closer, which marked the beginning a trend of mixing of EDM into pop that produced a series of forgettable releases and unexciting tunes that sound all too similar. Somewhere in there, pop lost its appeal. And with many of the major pop stars on hiatus, the necessity of the revival of pop is imminent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this sense, Taylor Swift is like a single-handed warrior that tries to save the waning pop scene besieged by hip-hop but is left aside. The road for pop will become narrower and more limited; an average hip-hop album might score good reception with the push of streaming platforms, but a high-quality pop record might not attain comparable success. In the coming years, pop stars will have to seek different sounds or bring something new to standout in the sea of mediocre hip-hop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><summary type="html">Reputation was the biggest album of 2018. There’s absolutely no doubt in that. It is also the best selling album of 2017. There’s no doubt in that either. But ever since its release, the media and others have criticized it as being Swift’s biggest flop in her career. But is it really? The simple answer is no. But if we dive deeper into the undercurrents, perhaps we would see the essence of the album more clearly.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/REP1.jpg" /></entry></feed>