<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-27T14:06:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/feed.xml</id><title type="html">rence</title><subtitle>a collection of thoughts by Lawrence Wang</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Lover: The Evolution of Taylor Swift</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/lover/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lover&amp;#58; The Evolution of Taylor Swift" /><published>2019-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/lover</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/lover/">&lt;p&gt;We all remember the vengeful spirit of Taylor Swift. From claiming that “there’s nothing I do better than revenge” to “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,” a certain part of her discography was dedicated to feuds and lost loves. In fact, just two years ago, Taylor Swift was busy burning bridges and throwing shades, (in addition to being &lt;em&gt;presumably dead&lt;/em&gt;) in the music video for “Look What You Made Me Do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;reputation&lt;/em&gt; were a product of the venom and frustration that occupied her in the aftermaths of the Kim-Kanye controversy, then &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; would be the complete antithesis of that. With her newest release, Taylor Swift delivers her most stylistically diverse and artistically complete body of work, featuring poignant introspection, playful maturity, and most importantly, a grand forgiveness, for both her enemies and herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the outcome of the drama, the creation of this album shows Taylor taking confident strides away from the days of bitter blame games. Realizing that contentions only feed into the bloodthirsty, clickbaity headline culture of today, Taylor also concludes that there are more important issues in life, such as the health of family members (“Soon You’ll Get Better”), political advocacy (“The Man”), and finding the one true love (“Lover”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-past-in-the-past&quot;&gt;A Past in the Past&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2006, Taylor Swift debuted as a country princess (&lt;em&gt;a petty one too&lt;/em&gt;). She was heralded as “America’s Sweetheart,” that curly-haired girl next door who sang about love stories and fairytales. To be fair, it was fine for the 17-years-old Taylor to be petty, to sing about failed relationships and shitty boyfriends. But it did become problematic when people, including herself, seemed to forget that sweethearts grow up too, just like prom queens do not stay young forever and memories someday fade. When she gradually became complacent to an immaturity that resorted to triviality and revenge, it felt like a stagnancy in her creative direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The halos also meant heightened expectation from fans and critics alike. During the release for &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, both Swift and her music were recognized as perfection in the Pop universe. She had the flawless image, soaring sales numbers, all-star team of friends, and an award-winning album. Yet while she has reaped the benefits of media exposure, she also suffered — because public perception is an odd thing - the same people that crowned you can turn against you just as quickly. In today’s &lt;em&gt;stan-or-canceled&lt;/em&gt; culture, the ideals demanded by the public can be exhausting. According to a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/taylor-swift-rolling-stone-interview-880794/&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with The Rolling Stone, Swift stated that “[people] decided in 2016 that absolutely everything about me was wrong. If I did something good, it was for the wrong reasons. If I did something brave, I didn’t do it correctly. If I stood up for myself, I was throwing a tantrum. And so I found myself in this endless mockery echo chamber.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/lover2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-beginning&quot;&gt;A New Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some bizarre way, however, her fall from grace also prompted the evolution of her artistry. Her once-teenager audience are now adults, and it seemed appropriate for her to grow out of the expectations and halos that once chained her. She did lose her perfect image, but in the death of her reputation, she became aware of the delicacy of herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Archer” is Swift’s attempt to face that delicate part of her. The drum beats build a looming anxiety that lasts for the entirety of the track, creating an anticipation for climax, yet never reaching a cathartic moment. By depicting the uncertainty inherent to love, the song also reminds us that uncertainty is simply a fact of life, that things often do not have definitive ends, that somethings just become forgotten, trail off, and reach nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that achingly sad moment of introspection, Taylor becomes aware of her shattered self as the veneers peeled away — she realizes that anyone can see right through her, just as she sings “I see right through me.” As the weariness finally washes over, the desperation for someone to stick around this time highlights precisely how there is no guarantee of it. After half a decade of jumping from romances, she understands that love stories are not as simple as “baby just say yes.” They may be complicated, messy, and inconclusive. Fairytales do not exist in real life, and if you want something, you have to fight for it — whether it be truth, vindication, or love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-grand-forgiveness&quot;&gt;A Grand Forgiveness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the lesson &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; brings is knowing ourselves. Understanding our own fragility makes us more accepting of others. Understanding our own defects makes us braver and more honest. “I Forgot That You Existed,” with playful and light presentation, contrasts greatly with the dark, gothic tracks from reputation. “It’s Nice To Have A Friend,” is the other side to “This Is Why We Can’t Have Nice Things.” Through a celebration of love and passion, she has learned to forgive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As dramas of the past dissipate, as the happy, the unhappy, the fortunate, and the unfortunate fade, Taylor Swift, in the spirit of moving on, bathes in “Daylight” and proclaims that “I wanna be defined by the things that I love. Not the things I hate. Not the things I’m afraid of, or the things that haunt me in the middle of the night.” She cannot remain America’s Sweetheart forever. Nobody can. Just like Rihanna’s modeling career and Gaga’s makeup line, there comes a time for Taylor to find her own voice. This time around, Taylor Swift announces that she will not be defined by resentment or snake emojis. Instead, she would like to be remembered by forgiveness, self-care, and maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone makes mistakes. We can all be seized by vengeance and rage. But more importantly, we also grow up, encounter ourselves, and find the things that matter more. Leaving the bad in the past — that is the victor’s attitude. Being defined by what you love — that is &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">We all remember the vengeful spirit of Taylor Swift. From claiming that “there’s nothing I do better than revenge” to “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,” a certain part of her discography was dedicated to feuds and lost loves. In fact, just two years ago, Taylor Swift was busy burning bridges and throwing shades, (in addition to being presumably dead) in the music video for “Look What You Made Me Do.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/lover1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">1989: It’s a Harry Styles Thing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/1989/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1989&amp;#58; It's a Harry Styles Thing" /><published>2019-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/1989</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/1989/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; was the album that took 2014 like storm. It’s known as a lot of things: the transformational work that marked the emergence of a pop queen from a country princess; the singer-songwriter’s comeback project to sweep all the award shows; the album that beat &lt;em&gt;To Pimp a Butterfly&lt;/em&gt; to Album of The Year at the 58th Grammy Awards; &lt;em&gt;you get the idea&lt;/em&gt;. But what intrigued me the most is how the album had &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harry Styles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; so blatantly written across its lyrical content and thematic presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taylor Swift has never had a shortage of boy friends: whether it be Joe Jonas, or John Mayer, or Tom Hiddleston. Concurrently, it’s never been rare for Swift to write about them: whether it be We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together, or Dear John, and Getaway Car, respectively. But in &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, Taylor documents her journey through love with a desolate determination, charming sweetness, and keen introspection. Taken together, the subject matter of every song— from New York City in Welcome to New York to London in Clean— chronicle the ups and downs in Swift and Styles’ relationship and narrate a most beautiful love story from beginning to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.billboard.com/files/media/taylor-swift-harry-styles-2012-billboard-1548_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-perfectly-styled-fantasy-story&quot;&gt;The Perfectly Styled Fantasy Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they first started dating in the winter of 2012, they seemed like the perfect couple. One Direction was the international phenomenon, Taylor Swift was America’s Sweetheart: both talented, both paragons of their respective sexes, both with impressive fan bases. Both living in NYC— topic of the album’s first song. Some might call it the worst New York anthem ever, but I think it may very well be a celebration of the historic decision to move to NYC that allowed this love affair to develop, and in that sense, introduction to the bittersweet romance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third track, Style has the most obvious connection to Harry. First of all, &lt;em&gt;the title&lt;/em&gt;. Second, the references, such as the “long hair, slicked back, white t-shirt” and the “James Dean daydream look in your eyes.” Third, Taylor said it herself in an interview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s basically one of those relationships that’s always a bit off. The two people are trying to forget each other. So, it’s like, “All right, I heard you went off with her,” and well, I’ve done that, too. My previous albums have also been sort of like, “I was right, you were wrong, you did this, it made me feel like this”—a righteous sense of right and wrong in a relationship. What happens when you grow up is you realize the rules in a relationship are very blurred and that it gets very complicated very quickly, and there’s not a case of who was right or who was wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship, according to Taylor, has never been a smooth ride. There’s been rumors of Harry Styles hooking up with other girls (which is semi-corroborated by herself). There’s been the thoughts of “Are we out of the woods yet? Are we in the clear yet?” in Out Of The Woods, the most vivid rendition of their love story on the album. We gain glimpses into their life together: the polaroid taken on their couch, the two paper airplane necklaces, the snowmobile accident during the skiing trip, the stitches and tears in the hospital room… All told with immense underlying emotion and, more importantly, bursting apprehension wondering whether the woods are just trees, where the next roadblock would be, how long this precious story would last, when it would end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In I Wish You Would, the two have broken up, but the regret is eating both of their minds alive. Taylor has allegedly said that the song is about her ex who “bought a house literally one road adjacent to hers.” In Perfect, Harry mirrors Taylor’s lines: “windows down, you pass my street, the memories start” with “and if you like midnight driving with the windows down.” The story goes that every night, he would drive home, accidentally turn into her street, because he wanted to tell her how “he just wants to stop by her house and see her,” but he never did— because he thought she hated him now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, what he didn’t know is that she also stayed up watching his headlights pass by her windowpane, that “she’s still in love with him.” All the while he’s deciding whether to turn up at her house at 2 A.M., she’s hoping that he would. Turn right back around. Know that she’d never forget him. Know that she misses him too much to be mad at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, that imperfect love is savored in Wildest Dream, in which Taylor wishes her lost love would see her in his dreams, and remember her the way he would remember him. No longer the vengeful spirit found in Better Than Revenge, Taylor’s first thoughts when entering a relationship are “when this ends, I hope it ends well. I hope you remember me well.” With imagery of the ocean and a maritime journey, This Love continues the reminiscence of the good times and the bad, as she relives moments of the love that left a permanent mark on her. As the sonic repetition of “this love” glide past our ears, we begin to feel those memories of love appearing and disappearing, but never leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything comes to a halt in Clean. Drafting dramatic metaphors of drought, the song symbolizes the absence of a relationship that once took up the artist’s entire world. For months all she could do was think about the good times. For months the memories haunted her. Until one day, all of a sudden, she realizes she’s been in London for two weeks and hasn’t thought about him. She’s fine, and she hopes he’s fine. In the pouring rain, the first thought that came to her mind was “I’m finally clean.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.vice.com/noisey/content-images/article/taylor-swift-1989-world-tour-review-essay/Screen-Shot-2015-07-13-at-11-40-25-AM.jpg?crop=1xw:0.9736752717391305xh;center,center&amp;amp;resize=1200:*&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-selling-coming-of-age-story&quot;&gt;The Best-Selling Coming-of-Age Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the story. Style outlines a timeless image. Out Of The Woods highlights a directionless anxiety. All You Had To Do Was Stay is the cheerful-tunes-shrouded melancholy of wanting it all back. How You Get The Girl is the instruction manual she wished he had followed to get her back. I Wish You Would conveys regret. This Love recounts the times that seem so beautiful in retrospect, and in Clean — it’s all gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, they did not end up together. I never cared much about their relationship before, but after listening to the album knowing the Harry Styles undertones and hints, I can’t help but imagine what might have happened if the two did end up together. What if they held onto each other and cherished each other? In interviews, members of One Direction were always making fun of Harry about Taylor. Weren’t they Perfect for each other? Weren’t they meant for each other? Weren’t they supposed to never go out of Style and always be each other’s Wildest Dreams?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the audience, all we could ever do is listen to what artists have to say. We will never get the full picture. We will never know how beautiful the love was, how intense the fall out was, how acute the heartache was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what we do know is that &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; exemplifies the artist’s transformation from the girl sitting on bleachers, looking out the window to the boy next door, believing in fairy tales — to a woman understanding that not every romance will end like a fairy tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an album about Harry Styles. It is an album to tell one story. Maybe it’s the love story of one fatalistic relationship. But more importantly, it’s a coming of age story of Taylor Swift. She realizes that not every relationship will have a knight in shining armor. She realizes fairy-tale endings are not a given, they are not how love is supposed to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think the way I used to approach relationships was very idealistic,” she says. “I used to go into them thinking, ‘Maybe this is the one — we’ll get married and have a family, this could be forever.’ Whereas now I go in thinking, ‘How long do we have on the clock — before something comes along and puts a wrench in it, or your publicist calls and says this isn’t a good idea?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/3584/3437428988_efb401a079_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-real-love-story&quot;&gt;The Real Love Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real love stories are not just the sassiness “she wears short skirts I wear T-shirts” or playfulness in “I can make a bad guy good for a weekend,” or the vengefulness in “she underestimated just who she was stealing from.” Love is more than seeing that single face in every crowd, and breakup is more than pointing fingers. It can be messy, difficult, painful. The lines are blurred. The right and wrong are mingled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; is more than a best-selling pop album, it tells the story of growth, of maturing, of self-discovery. Of a princess finding her prince charming but without a happily-ever-after. In her sophomore album Fearless, Taylor Swift used one chart-topping single to characterize an endearing love story. With &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, it took her an entire album to do so. It’s a love story without “baby just say yes,” but it is more empowering, more precious, and more real, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real love story is bittersweet, not nearly as dreamy as Love Story. But it’s more lively and contains much more strength. It comes with the realizations that love is not one-size-fits-all, that there might never be a happily-ever-after, and that resolutions might never exist. The anxiety might be overwhelming; the heartbreak might be unbearable. That’s what real love takes. That’s what make us believe that the imperfections in the fact that “I’m just a guy you’ll write breakup songs about” make the “red lips, little skirt, long hair, white t-shirt” style truly perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some information are excerpted from Tumblr.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><summary type="html">1989 was the album that took 2014 like storm. It’s known as a lot of things: the transformational work that marked the emergence of a pop queen from a country princess; the singer-songwriter’s comeback project to sweep all the award shows; the album that beat To Pimp a Butterfly to Album of The Year at the 58th Grammy Awards; you get the idea. But what intrigued me the most is how the album had Harry Styles so blatantly written across its lyrical content and thematic presentation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/blog/master/assets/images/1989.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Russian Doll: It’s Hard to Stay Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/russian-doll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Russian Doll&amp;#58; It's Hard to Stay Alive" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/russian-doll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/russian-doll/">&lt;p&gt;You would think that after an entire school year of Nietzsche, Meursault, Godot, Kafka, Hemingway, and &lt;em&gt;Like Water for Chocolate&lt;/em&gt; in International Baccalaureate English would be enough absurdist discussion for a while, if not an entire lifetime. But &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt;, the extremely odd, extremely beautiful, and extremely thought-provoking delight, proved to be just that piece of existentialism I never knew I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer brilliance in the editing and cinematography is just the least of it: the message is what I find to be the most interesting. Particularly, the message that “it’s too easy to die that it’s hard to stay alive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series is deeply absurd, with the protagonist running into death in the most unexpected, dark-humor ways — at times, it’s nearly the real life version of Dumb Ways To Die. It’s also deeply existential, with a beautifully-crafted dialogue on which parts of the numerous ways to die actually convey the essence of life. It’s a story about two equally unfortunate people finding their own meaning of existence, and somehow that’s incredibly grand and moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nadias-dilemma&quot;&gt;Nadia’s Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time passes by linearly throughout the show, but the main character, Nadia, is stuck on the night of her birthday party — the recycled moments of her waking up in front of the bathroom mirror is a diametric symbol of death and rebirth. Nadia and the other protagonist, Alan, theorized that the seemingly eternal time-loop is a punishment for their mistakes during their childhood. Nadia wanted to leave her mother, and attributed her mother’s death to her own fault, after which she decided to push other people away to avoid any possibility of genuine connection that might end up hurting both parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But through the eyes of Ruth, Nadia’s life-long friend and mentor, it was never Nadia’s fault. She was a tiny seed buried in darkness fighting her way to the light. She wanted to &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt;, and “it’s the most beautiful thing in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ruth speaks arguably the most touching line of the series: “Do you still have that in you? I look at you now, chasing down death at every corner. Sweetheart, where is that gorgeous piece of you pushing to be a part of this world?” Nadia tears up, as would anyone who has felt the powerlessness of barely living, day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nadia is not a completely good person. Sometimes she’s not kind enough, or proactive enough, or friendly enough — she knows that about herself, so while she’s unforgiving of everything around her, that cynical attitude also extends to herself. She would appear tough, nonchalant, totally untouchable, absolutely inconsiderate, the consequences of which include a deep feeling of isolation and emptiness that can not be cured by the alcohol, or random sexual encounters, or an israeli-joint-highlighted birthday party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that’s her defense mechanism, of closing herself off from the world, thus eliminating the possibility of getting hurt and hurting other people. Or perhaps that’s who we all are — &lt;em&gt;incompletely good&lt;/em&gt; — as a result of our tendency to avoid pain and discomfort. But may I suggest to you that the experiences of bruising, the pain inherent to love, hate, and betrayal are the most real, human things, and that when we insulate ourselves from the world, we lose parts of what make us human in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/RD2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-is-not-the-end&quot;&gt;It Is Not The End&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ending is a beautiful moment. It has a quality that is as promising as &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt;, but not quite &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt;. The two protagonists reappear in front of their bathroom mirrors one last time and realize they are in different dimensions — the other person is back in cycle #1 and has no recollection of the death-defying adventures they shared together. Now, they have to look for the other person and convince them that all those hundreds of attempts at living and dying were actually real. As the screen splits in half, the audience witnesses a hopeful Alan assisting the turbulent Nadia, and a patient Nadia comforting the confused Alan. And as they walk through the winter New York streets, the two screens merge into one, with a renewed Nadia holding a torch, finally, again, pushing to be a part of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the mediocrity of daily chores and the pressures from expectations can make life feel like hell, like purgatory on earth. Sometimes, the anxiety of being alive strikes blows to us that seem impossible to handle. But as &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt; reminds us, &lt;strong&gt;we are not alone in this world&lt;/strong&gt;. We still have each other, can find each other, and save each other. Just like in the ending when Nadia and Alan march, joining Horse’s parade of monsters, passing the shoulders of their alternative selves — &lt;em&gt;they have not given up on each other&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world out there can be a vile one. A lonely one. A troubled one. One in which it’s hard to stay alive. But if we can all dig into our hearts, see ourselves for who we are, and learn to forgive and reconcile, maybe we can also let go of the cold, exoskeletal shells of protective covers; let go of the habit of keeping people at a distance; let go of the need to hide our insecurities and conceal our mistakes. In doing so, perhaps we might rediscover the fine world that is worth fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May this newfound hope and companionship in &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt; mean that the past moments of “I just want to die” are not the end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Television" /><category term="Netflix" /><category term="TV" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">You would think that after an entire school year of Nietzsche, Meursault, Godot, Kafka, Hemingway, and Like Water for Chocolate in International Baccalaureate English would be enough absurdist discussion for a while, if not an entire lifetime. But Russian Doll, the extremely odd, extremely beautiful, and extremely thought-provoking delight, proved to be just that piece of existentialism I never knew I needed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/RD1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">La La Land: A Not-So-Happily Ever After</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/la-la-land/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="La La Land&amp;#58; A Not-So-Happily Ever After" /><published>2018-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/la-la-land</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/la-la-land/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is charming like nothing else: the sentimental music, the fanciful images, the idealistic story— everything is  romantically mesmerizing. Chazelle’s previous work, &lt;em&gt;Whiplash&lt;/em&gt;, was similarly impressive. But &lt;em&gt;Whiplash&lt;/em&gt; was angry, hysterical, dangerous, saturated with sweat, tear, blood, and a risky devotion, whereas &lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is clear, transparent, with a dreamy magnificence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easily one of the best films of 2016, but the imperfect ending makes many wonder if it vibed with the holidays and Valentines season. However, may I suggest that it is precisely the imperfection that makes this story of lovers and dreamers real, precious, and unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is charming like nothing else: the sentimental music, the fanciful images, the idealistic story — everything is  romantically mesmerizing. Chazelle’s previous work, &lt;em&gt;Whiplash&lt;/em&gt;, was similarly impressive. But &lt;em&gt;Whiplash&lt;/em&gt; was angry, hysterical, dangerous, saturated with sweat, tear, blood, and a risky devotion, whereas &lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is clear, transparent, with a dreamy magnificence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easily one of the best films of 2016, but the imperfect ending makes many wonder if it vibed with the holidays and Valentines season. However, may I suggest that it is precisely the imperfection that makes this story of lovers and dreamers real, precious, and unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-love-and-dreams&quot;&gt;The Love and Dreams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, Sebastian and Mia were never meant for each other. In life’s lowest points, love and friendship might be better described as the desperate need for someone to whom one can vent the pessimism and from whom one might extract encouragement - and that was the case for Mia and Sebastian. They saw their failures, their unrecognized efforts, their dreams in each other, and they mistook the commonality in their misfortune as love, expressed through words of comfort for their unrealistic hopes. It sounds romantic on paper, but not so pretty in practice. They would argue about minute details, which is not unusual for couples, but when they fail to adapt to each other’s values and expectations, is it realisitc for them to manage living together for the rest of their lives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy utter the words “I love you,” but loving takes much more than a three-syllable phrase. To love is to take the responsibility of your actions and to accept the weaknesses in yourself and your partner. We can’t all be perfect, but similarly, we can’t always live in such grand self-consolation, where we tell ourselves we’re in love but really we’re just selfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mia is selfish. She’s had a successful, rich boyfriend whom she dumped. So why did she choose Sebastian? It’s because she sees herself in him: the dejected dream chaser. In reality, however, she was never going to give up everything for him. When Sebastian was slowly becoming the musician he’s always wanted to be, she wanted him to admit that he wasn’t happy. But Sebastian does love music, and who said he didn’t love touring? Mia felt imbalanced: when the dreams they associated with each other came true, they suddenly couldn’t bear each other anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the dream that unites them is precisely what separates them. Sebastian thought he found the love of his life, but it’s nothing more than in a particular place, at a particular time, he met someone who needed someone. In the end, they both loved their dreams more than they loved love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/LLL1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dream-of-stars&quot;&gt;The Dream of Stars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe, neither of them needed a happily-ever-after. LA has boundless deserts, but at the end of those deserts, there’s the splendor of the city and the equally boundless sea. When the blue ocean embraces the blue sky, it’s just like idealists embracing the ephemeral joy, even if thunderclouds might descend the very next second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countless dreamers, like Mia, come to Hollywood in search of their aspirations. Countless dreams are shattered here. Yet for as long as there’s people young and old, searching, looking, the stars will never dim, and everything will always be ever so glorious. This city of star is the lovely night under the purplish nightfall, the pier shrouded by the brilliant dawn, the dinner club with a piano lit by the dim lamp light. It’s where music never stops. It’s a dreamland where all the colors are bright, pure, where even the air seems intoxicated with sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does such a charming world exist? We all know the answer to that. The road to dreams is difficult, with steep and rocky inclines, with thorns and spikes and prickles. The city of star doesn’t shine for anyone in particular. The people who realize their dreams are few, yet who can say, with confidence, that those who try are fools?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-high-road&quot;&gt;The High Road&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dreams are the constant variables in everyone’s life. Some change, some are given up, but some have been kept all along. At the end of the film, the two met in the jazz club, both clutching their dreams. When their eyes met, both watery, were they not smiling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;La La Land&lt;/em&gt; is also nowhere near a tragedy. After all, Sebastian and Mia held on to their aspirations. Both became what they wanted to be. Both conquered the unthinkable future of the once discouraged dreamers. Both lived exactly as they imagined 5 years ago: the girl now a renowned star, the guy now owning a jazz club — not many can afford such luxury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the love, it forged both of their lives. Intentionally or not, they have affected each other’s decision at an important junction. The two came together on the way to their dreams, and one pushed the other to success. Both of their dreams came true at the cost of losing each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, they both found that someone in the crowd, whom they’ve waited for, whom they needed to know. After they’ve lifted each other off the ground, they went on to continue their lives. They might not have been ready to wholeheartedly love each other, but they did wholeheartedly need each other, help each other, and succeed &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; each other. And as such, despite the regrets and what-ifs, who can say that a not-happily ever after is not splendid as well?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Movie" /><category term="La La Land" /><category term="Musical" /><category term="Dream" /><category term="Movie" /><summary type="html">La La Land is charming like nothing else: the sentimental music, the fanciful images, the idealistic story— everything is romantically mesmerizing. Chazelle’s previous work, Whiplash, was similarly impressive. But Whiplash was angry, hysterical, dangerous, saturated with sweat, tear, blood, and a risky devotion, whereas La La Land is clear, transparent, with a dreamy magnificence.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/LLL2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Reputation: A Career-Ending Flop?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/reputation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reputation&amp;#58; A Career-Ending Flop?" /><published>2018-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/reputation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/reputation/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; was the biggest album of 2018. There’s absolutely no doubt in that. It is also the best selling album of 2017. There’s no doubt in that either. But ever since its release, the media and others have criticized it as being Swift’s biggest flop in her career. But is it really? The simple answer is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. But if we dive deeper into the undercurrents, perhaps we would see the essence of the album more clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-drama&quot;&gt;The Drama&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast backward three years, the release of &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;phenomenal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It was heralded as the most iconic, textbook example pop record of the 21st century. Through the sound and delivery, Swift created a world that mixes the vintage and modern, that’s both nostalgic and energetic. A world that places love, and more importantly, the courage to love, on a towering pedestal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the aftermath of the 1989 era was not pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the summer of 2016 unraveled, Swift’s “American Sweetheart” image shattered. Overnight, the media’s perception of her turned from the relatable country princess turned pop queen to a nasty snake suffering from victimhood complex. From Kanye West’s “Famous” (and its music video) to Kim Kardashian’s rapid fire attacks to the god awful breakup with Calvin Harris for songwriting credit claims to the rebound of Tom Hiddleston that lasted a total of 3 seconds, Swift’s reputation suffered and plummeted and crashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The friends she once had, or partied with, or went on the Victoria’s Secret runway with, or made music videos with turned against her. The media that once adored and supported her slandered her. The innocently misled public again showed their viciousness and flooded her social media with the snake emoji. And although it’s impossible for us outsiders to know what really happened underneath the drama, it’s undeniable that the happenstances of that summer seriously affected Swift and fueled the creation of this album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://seatgeek.com/tba/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/taylor-swift_promo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-album&quot;&gt;The Album&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, she took a one year break from releasing material, which was unprecedented to say the least and severely hampered her systematic release schedule. But then came &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt;, an introspective saga about the aftermath of the collapse of a pop queen’s impeccable reputation— the entire album feels more like Swift’s journey of making peace with the taint in her public image than a traditional love-pop album or diss album. She starts her journey with no sense of remorse whatsoever in I Did Something Bad and Don’t Blame Me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But if he drops my name, then I owe him nothin’ &lt;br /&gt;
And if he spends my change, then he had it comin’ &lt;br /&gt;
Don’t blame me, love made me crazy  &lt;br /&gt;
If it doesn’t, you ain’t doin’ it right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But gradually, that strength she feigns and desire for vengeance seems to fade away, as she scores a new love, a love that is delicate and pure, yet unbreakable by the rumors and defamation. The mid-album songs, such as Gorgeous, King of My Heart, and Dancing With Our Hands Tied, give off a 1989-ish sentiment regarding love, although presented with choppier and darker songwriting. Towards the end of the album, time and love together have been able to heal the scars left behind by the smearing criticisms. In This Is Why We Can’t Have Nice Things, Swift makes snarky remarks that point at specific people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Friends don’t try to trick you&lt;br /&gt;
Get you on the phone and mind-twist you &lt;br /&gt;
But I’m not the only friend you’ve lost lately&lt;br /&gt;
If only you weren’t so shady&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through joking about the agony and injury of the past, she proves that she has grown, that she is indeed beyond the drama, that she has let it go like clouds blown away by the winter wind. Call It What You Want is the final statement that marks the attitude of the Reputation era. Her castle of friends that she used to fortify herself against her insecurities crumbled. Her unpreparedness in the fight forecasted her defeat. She lost her crown, yet in the end, she found something greater. She lost her impeccable reputation, but that’s alright, because she’s stronger now, and the media can really just call it what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sonically speaking, the album mixes elements that are indeed new to Taylor Swift albums, with a greater emphasis on electronic and hip-hop influences. Lyrically speaking, the album is as strong as ever, and Getaway Car is the prime example of that. The entire song tells such a vivid and convincing story of a love that was doomed to fail since its conception. The contrasting colors create an ominous atmosphere while the couplets forge a rhyme scheme that strongly aligns with the beat. The lines easily morph into visuals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Well, he was runnin’ after us, I was screamin’, “Go, go, go!” &lt;br /&gt;
But with three of us, honey, it’s a sideshow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And my personal favorite part comes with the bridge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m in a getaway car  &lt;br /&gt;
I left you in a motel bar &lt;br /&gt;
Put the money in a bag and I stole the keys &lt;br /&gt;
That was the last time you ever saw me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She leaves him with no regret. Takes the money and the keys.  Just like how she rode in the car, cried in the car, flew in the car, now she’ll leave in the car. With a light push on the gas pedal and she’s gone, leaving the dusts dancing behind the getaway car. The story is fateful, and brutally honest, the exact same brand of honesty in storytelling that serves as the hallmark of all her songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first half of the album, Swift discusses reputation and dreams of revenge in tracks shrouded with a dark, industrial voltage. Yet in the second half, she continues the iconic vibe of 1989 that pushes the passion of love to momentous heights. She climbed up the ruins of her wounded reputation, and then found salvation in love— that’s a concept that everyone can relate to. Thus, the listening experience is the audience’s journey, along with Swift, to find the exit to the pain and the gleaming sun of a newfound comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.philly.com/resizer/aDjqN0LW_l-NmG96oVQuPCcpjX8=/1400x0/center/middle/arc-anglerfish-arc2-prod-pmn.s3.amazonaws.com/public/T45JUACWFNFHJLT23COTJZ3K6M.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Section&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-verdict&quot;&gt;The Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of success, &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; was a gigantic commercial success. In a world with streaming dominating the scene, Taylor Swift is one of the few artists that can sell a million copies in the first week. Aside from sales, the Reputation Stadium Tour grossed 345.7 million dollars, which is 100 million more than the 1989 World Tour with 50% less shows. &lt;em&gt;Also making it the &lt;strong&gt;second highest&lt;/strong&gt; per show gross in the history of concert tours&lt;/em&gt;. The production of the tour doubtlessly makes it the best of 2018, with marvelous performances from eras old and new, incredible choreography, and stunning stage design and fireworks. Without essentially any promotion, the fact that Reputation accomplished all of the above is absolutely phenomenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; is an unmissable album from 2017, and I was rather speechless when it wasn’t nominated for Album of the Year at the 2019 Grammys, especially since it’s the first year of expanded nominations. In fact, similar to &lt;em&gt;Speak Now&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; did not receive any General Field nominations, and like &lt;em&gt;Red&lt;/em&gt;, it did not win a single Grammy. This might mean that &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; is a flop according to Swift’s standards, or at least, the Old Taylor’s standards. I mean, remember how she went on to make &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; to slap the Recording Academy in the face after her defeat with &lt;em&gt;Red&lt;/em&gt;? But then again, the Old Taylor is dead, and perhaps she is simply tired of the massive routine promotional effort behind a Grammy run. With 10 Grammys in her pocket and gracefully marching into her late 20s, maybe what we are seeing is, in addition to a sincere reflection of a lost prestige, a growth and maturity signifying that she’s unbothered by cosmetics like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, looking at the other nominees this year in the General Field, we are seeing a growing dominance of hip-hop. Whether this is due to the rise of streaming platforms or the Recording Academy’s attempt at “inclusivity,” it’s undeniable that hip-hop is becoming the new “pop.” No matter how some dislike the new sound, or how the promotion is lacking, it’s hard to deny that &lt;em&gt;Reputation&lt;/em&gt; is a successful pop record that totally deserves to be nominated, and entries like End Game and Delicate totally merit a nomination and even the award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps &lt;em&gt;Reputation’s&lt;/em&gt; “flop” is a portrayal of a larger phenomenon: the decline of pop as a genre. A phenomenon that started with The Chainsmokers’ Closer, which marked the beginning a trend of mixing of EDM into pop that produced a series of forgettable releases and unexciting tunes that sound all too similar. Somewhere in there, pop lost its appeal. And with many of the major pop stars on hiatus, the necessity of the revival of pop is imminent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this sense, Taylor Swift is like a single-handed warrior that tries to save the waning pop scene besieged by hip-hop but is left aside. The road for pop will become narrower and more limited; an average hip-hop album might score good reception with the push of streaming platforms, but a high-quality pop record might not attain comparable success. In the coming years, pop stars will have to seek different sounds or bring something new to standout in the sea of mediocre hip-hop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><summary type="html">Reputation was the biggest album of 2018. There’s absolutely no doubt in that. It is also the best selling album of 2017. There’s no doubt in that either. But ever since its release, the media and others have criticized it as being Swift’s biggest flop in her career. But is it really? The simple answer is no. But if we dive deeper into the undercurrents, perhaps we would see the essence of the album more clearly.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/REP1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Melodrama: The Glamour and Trauma Became Us</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/melodrama/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Melodrama&amp;#58; The Glamour and Trauma Became Us" /><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/melodrama</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/melodrama/">&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;Pure Heroine&lt;/em&gt; was about teenage Lorde’s idea of maturity, her imagination of what the adult world must be like, then her sophomore album is precisely the opposite. &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; is cool— the toned quality materializes through the predominantly blue album art. And with this record, the brilliant facade of the adult world peels off layer by layer, until all that’s left is the delicate, jaded, melancholic core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Antonoff’s production adds another coating of complexity and unforgettable projection to Lorde’s end-of-adolescence state of mind: the youth slipping away on the light-up floor, the secluded utopia of careless parties, the love that burns so bright and then breaks into pieces. It touches the solemn and fateful side of this initiation rite of adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-never-ending-party&quot;&gt;A Never-Ending Party&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; were a party, then Green Light marks the start of the journey of a “drunk girl at the party dancing around crying about her ex-boyfriend who everyone thinks is a mess.” The lead single has such a sense of finality to it, opening the album with a mysterious, cool-colored yet charming story of a new beginning. The mindless carousing continues even though no one knows what might happen when they’re Sober. Or perhaps “pretending that we don’t care” is just another part of adulthood? After all, “going astray with me” is only an attitude to life. Yes, leaving in the morning will hurt, hearts will ache, but why not take this moment to dance with us? Perhaps losing a bit of our minds will be good for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liability is the turning point, the moment of self-reflective weakness. In the dead of night, as the party continues, we go off to the bathroom and see ourselves in the mirror— the terrible, mess of a self. And we realize the horrifying, underlying truth— what exactly does it take to grow up? Compromising our identity? Exposing the most delicate parts ourselves to the devouring of others? That’s when the revelation comes so strikingly poignant: as the lights turn on and the people go home, as we lose ourselves in the distrust and cold-shoulder of others, as the youthful part of ourselves, the innocent dreams of past time depart and fade away in the waters borne ceaselessly into the past, what do we have left?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, love and breakups are quintessential to any grow up story. The remarkable romanticism of the album is apparent in The Louvre through the literary devices: the personification of summer, the days and nights that are “perfumed” with obsession present the beauty of an endearing love. Yet as suggested by the uneasy beats of the track, that beauty, so alarmingly coated in sacrifice, eventually will fall apart. With the somber recount of the aftermath of the break up in Hard Feelings, we are introduced to the winter, the death of the rushing feelings that were once so strong, so domineering, so relentless. Ultimately, as comfortable as being underneath summer’s tongue was, there comes a day when we all have to let go of that endless summer afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-the-end-of-one-to-the-start-of-another&quot;&gt;From the End of One to the Start of Another&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme is then reinforced through Sober II (Melodrama) and Writer In The Dark. The love ends, romance is succeeded by melodrama. In the blinding fumes of accusations, we realize that we always knew we would end up here; it’s only in the psycho-high kind of self-indulgence did we forget that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;They’ll talk about us, all the lovers&lt;br /&gt;
How we kiss and kill each other.&lt;br /&gt;
They’ll talk about us, and discover&lt;br /&gt;
How we kissed and killed each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet we can’t help but reminiscing the magic and love and tender touches in the car that characterized the summertimes, before the blizzard hit the town and we had to board up the windows and retreat into solitude. And in that contemplation, we arrive at the conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All of the dreams that get harder,&lt;br /&gt;
All of the things that I offer you,&lt;br /&gt;
All of the shit that we harbour,&lt;br /&gt;
But you’re not what you thought you were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the grand finale, we dump it all away in Perfect Places. In a sense, this last track summarizes the entire story, from the party to the fragility, from the love to no-more-love. In the graceless night, we are wild and young for the one last time. &lt;em&gt;Dancing. Proclaiming we are all-right. Yelling to the heavens, trying to prove the perfect place that doesn’t exist.&lt;/em&gt; We try to get there, but we never will. We are doomed to fail, but we carry on. And isn’t precisely this kind of valor, of trying in spite of challenges that is so admirable about the transition from adolescence into adulthood?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;melodrama-and-us&quot;&gt;Melodrama and Us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The album is titled melodrama, romance love affairs. Yet the album is not simply about breaking up, or even love. It seems closer to a diary to oneself, about how to manage the solitude, how to understand the ever-so complex notion of self— all of that, wrapped in strong sonic and lyrical cohesion. This is a part of why I was absolutely dumbfounded when &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; was snubbed of its album of the year. The journey Lorde presents shows the audience a meditation on the loneliness of an ambitious pop drama queen. The intimate vocals, lyrics, productions here are all Grammy’s worthy— yet all of that paled in face of the 60th Annual Grammy Awards’ pursuit of “equality” and “representation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all, the fragility of breakups, the confusion of growing up, the depravity of carousing, the loneliness of sobriety, the fiery emotions of adulthood— &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; contains all of these. And through editing life into one endless party, the good, the bad, the glamour, the trauma all invariably arrive at who we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorde’s idea of youth is acute, indulging, complete and unconditional. So many melodrama will end up being supercuts. So many hard feelings will lead to exclamation of what the fuck are perfect places. Perhaps this youth is imperfect, but its stubborn, tenacious, yet sinister vitality is precious and impossible to compound.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Lorde" /><category term="Pop" /><category term="Featured" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">If Pure Heroine was about teenage Lorde’s idea of maturity, her imagination of what the adult world must be like, then her sophomore album is precisely the opposite. Melodrama is cool— the toned quality materializes through the predominantly blue album art. And with this record, the brilliant facade of the adult world peels off layer by layer, until all that’s left is the delicate, jaded, melancholic core.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/MEL.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Prestige: Twisted Obsessions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/the-prestige/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Prestige&amp;#58; Twisted Obsessions" /><published>2018-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/the-prestige</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/the-prestige/">&lt;p&gt;When people think of Christopher Nolan, the first movies that pop into mind are probably the likes of &lt;em&gt;Inception&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Interstellar&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Dark Knight&lt;/em&gt;, the high-grossing international sensations that constructed the fan base of his cinematic empire. But to me, the often overlooked 2006 classic, The Prestige, might be one of the most iconic pieces of Nolan’s story telling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What The Prestige really comes down to is just Nolan flexing his control of nonlinear narrative structure. The disordered sequence of the narration becomes increasingly mesmerizing as we dive deeper into the film. For example, we won’t know until the very end, that the opening cut of the film is actually the last occurrence in the story. Amazing. I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intricate details like this offer bits of brain-burning fun, as we struggle to piece the seemingly disorganized story together, yet it does not come across as overwhelming. That is precisely the beauty behind many of Nolan’s works, and it’s infinitesimally augmented here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tragedy&quot;&gt;The Tragedy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the interweaving narratives, the film closely follows the central idea of passion and its toxic byproduct, obsession. The protagonists, Angier and Borden, are obsessed with magic, an obsession that transcends their worldly status and human limitations. They are plagued by a blinding desire that created a cognitive dissonance and littered them mental stability, driving them into the abyss of sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angier’s passion for magic prompts him to conceal his identity of a noble and become a magician’s protegee. He sacrifices his dignity, comforts, and eventually his wife. The sacrifice breeds more obsession which prompts even more sacrifice. &lt;em&gt;So what is all the sacrifice for?&lt;/em&gt; Ultimately, he lost more than status and love. As Angier adopted Tesla’s machine, it began the chapter of his final sacrifice— the sacrifice of self: behind every incredible show of magic, there is one rightful murder. The murderer Angier, the victim also Angier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tragedy is that if you examine Angier close enough, you would find he loves magic no more than the audience’s reaction. He’s obsessed with the surprised faces on people, not the art of magic. His obsession is fundamentally a false one, a mere projection of the prestige— completely extrinsic. But what is the value in external gratification? He thought he was obsessed with the magic that he loves, yet in the end, he’s lost in the congratulatory praises. Maybe starting from the moment he desperately tries to surpass Borden’s incredible trick, Angier has already lost himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angier started with a pure love for magic, so decided to assume a fake identity to break away from the constraints of his noble status. &lt;em&gt;Completely noble.&lt;/em&gt; But passion drew him closer and closer to hell. Until finally, his need to be better than Borden, to ride on top of Borden, to possess a trick better than Borden made his demise inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often times we are told that if we live the life prescribed to us, we’d be losing our identity. But how often do we consider the possibility of losing our true self on the way to personal freedom and validation? Maybe in the end, what matters is not the conflict between freedom or tradition, but that when we look back as we are halfway through our lives, we can still confidently say that we never strayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;human-human&quot;&gt;Human? Human.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a cinematic point of view, Nolan completely nailed the narrative and script. The story is beautifully crafted, but also one I find hard to bring myself to like. The performances of Christian Bale and Jack Hughman are beyond amazing. Yet while watching it on my 6-hour flight from LA to NYC, I couldn’t help but abhor the characters. They are all incredibly hateful, incredibly possessive, competitive, the darkest possible portrayal of human nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angier and Borden’s idea of obsession sucks every last drop of kindness from them and leaves them with nothing more than an empty, antihuman shell. Their vengeance paints them completely black, without any hint of the sparkly color of humanity. Even though the script actively tries to bring in elements such as children and birds and love, the story as a whole turns out to be entirely grim and cold, chilling to the bones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet in the end, however, it’s hard to say that they are not human. The competition between Borden and Angier composes a nasty, twisted tale of human dissatisfaction and selfishness, but it is still humanity. There’s the positive side of humanity, but also the negative side. No one can say they’ve never been obsessed, or selfish, or hurt others in our way to success. Perhaps we are all in this together. The film merely amplifies that. It may be dark, but it’s still human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-words&quot;&gt;Final Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found to be particularly interesting is the monologue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now you’re looking for the secret… but you won’t find it, because of course you’re not really looking. You don’t really want to know. You want to be fooled.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the film, Angier and Borden both wrote journals. Fake journals, more like. Full of things they want the other person to see. They tried to decipher each other’s journal, tried to look for the secret. They were both convinced that they found each other’s secret. But did they? They believed what they wanted to believe. In other words, they wanted to be fooled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, isn’t that just life? We are always seeing things, we are always looking for things. But are we really looking? Do we really want to know? Aren’t we simply concealing the delicate truth from ourselves? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aren’t we all fooled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Movie" /><category term="The Prestige" /><category term="Nolan" /><category term="Movie" /><summary type="html">When people think of Christopher Nolan, the first movies that pop into mind are probably the likes of Inception or Interstellar or The Dark Knight, the high-grossing international sensations that constructed the fan base of his cinematic empire. But to me, the often overlooked 2006 classic, The Prestige, might be one of the most iconic pieces of Nolan’s story telling.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/the_prestige.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hero: What Is a Hero?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/hero/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hero&amp;#58; What Is a Hero?" /><published>2017-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/hero</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/hero/">&lt;p&gt;Breaking into the Chinese film market in 2002, &lt;em&gt;Hero&lt;/em&gt; became the box office legend of the year. Though it still remains one of the biggest domestic releases of all time, many Chinese film critics at the time criticized the story for being too simple, that it only had beautiful pictures but lacked a soul. Internationally, however, &lt;em&gt;Hero&lt;/em&gt; did extremely well as it was nominated for Best Foreign Film at the 2003 Oscars. Regardless, &lt;em&gt;Hero&lt;/em&gt; marked a milestone for the Chinese film industry. After its release, the industry prospered in an era of big investment and big production business model, forging a period of immense growth in the film market in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hero succeeded in its poetic and creative visual representation. For Yimou Zhang, Hero is the revolutionary transition which debuted a new audio-visual depiction that became intrinsic to his style. During a period of lack of Chinese productions in the global and domestic markets alike, Zhang presented this visual refreshment for his audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;colors-in-hero&quot;&gt;Colors in &lt;em&gt;Hero&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Color is an important strategy Zhang employed in the film. In Wuming’s first story, everything from clothing to drapery to decoration are red, symbolizing passion, suspicion, conflict, and impulse. During the scene when the Zhao students bravely face their death, red also represents the blazing, relentless patriotism and a spirit that immortalizes their lives. In the Emperor’s version of the story, blue is the dominant color, representing solemnness and composure and showing the wisdom and thoroughness in his thinking. Green indicates life: in the first plot against the Emperor, the black palace is adorned with bright green drapery, symbolizing the assassins’ hope and faith for restoring peace in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Black is oppressive, cold, brutal, and, above all, lonely. In the film, black represents the prestige and strength of the Qin Empire. In the Emperor’s world, the palace is black, the armory is black, the soldiers are black. The hero is freed in the cruel darkness, but the Emperor is meant to fall into the restraints of that oppressive black crown representing ultimate authority. The black that surrounds him signifies that even if one day he does unite the world or amass all the wealth of the world, he will still be alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, during the martial arts sequence, Zhang utilizes a classic strategy of Chinese painting— freehand brush stroke. As opposed to the sharpness of the blade, the characters fight with the extraordinary conception of the mind. The lack of colors and the paucity of sounds during the action sequence create an atmosphere of heroic sacrifice. Through conveying the idea of ink-wash painting through martial arts, Zhang expresses the Chinese brand of philosophy, and perhaps, his attempt at advancing the Chinese culture in the international society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-hero&quot;&gt;What Is a Hero?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other important part of the film answers the essential question: what is a hero? From a certain perspective, everyone in the film is a hero. For the students willing to give up their lives for their country, their staunch spirit makes them heroes. For Changkong and Feixue who spent their lives for the goal of assassinating the Emperor, their integrity and trust in Wuming make them heroes too. Wuming, in order for prosperity and peace to once again descend on the land, gave up the assassination. This righteousness, justice, and impartial morality make him a hero. As for the Emperor, his respect for his opponents and his vision and foresight that allows the end to the suffering of many millions also make him a hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s precisely because of these heroes who fearlessly challenge death in face of calamity, who selflessly give up their personal goals for the greater good, who willingly take on infamy for the wellbeing of the world, humanity has been and will be continued.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Movie" /><category term="Chinese" /><category term="Zhang" /><category term="Movie" /><summary type="html">Breaking into the Chinese film market in 2002, Hero became the box office legend of the year. Though it still remains one of the biggest domestic releases of all time, many Chinese film critics at the time criticized the story for being too simple, that it only had beautiful pictures but lacked a soul. Internationally, however, Hero did extremely well as it was nominated for Best Foreign Film at the 2003 Oscars. Regardless, Hero marked a milestone for the Chinese film industry. After its release, the industry prospered in an era of big investment and big production business model, forging a period of immense growth in the film market in China.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/Hero.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Great Gatsby: How He Lost Himself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hello/gatsby/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Great Gatsby&amp;#58; How He Lost Himself" /><published>2017-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hello/gatsby</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hello/gatsby/">&lt;p&gt;Dreams are aspirations, yet less tangible. They are imaginations, yet more boundless. They are the instantaneous outburst of inner drive expressed in terms of outward hope. They represent all the hate about the present and all that will be marvelous in the future. They are the ultimate capacity for limitless creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So came the concept of the American Dream, the climax of the life of anyone born on this land of hope and opportunity. It started as the wish to own a piece of land and live a self-sufficient life, and gradually evolved into the intense desire to climb the social ladder— to become better, to reach higher. Even though it’s a dream with which few saw success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In two hundred years, generations upon generations of immigrants came to America to rid themselves of their past. Sailing past the Statue of Liberty, passing under the Golden Gate Bridge, marching across Long Beach, everyone who came believed that no matter hideous their past, how oppressive their destitute, as long as they work hard, persist, and endure, they will earn what they deserved: wealth, status, respect, love. Everyone who came had a dream, their own green light. &lt;strong&gt;Everyone is a Gatsby.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gatsby-flawed-greatness&quot;&gt;Gatsby: Flawed Greatness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t say Gatsby failed to achieve the material aspect of the American Dream. He does get rich. Mansion on Long Island: check. New yacht: check. Wall full of books: check. New name: check. Even his father, upon visiting his mansion for the first time for his funeral, said that he’s proud of Gatsby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe Daisy can be interpreted as a positive influence that encouraged him to challenge his situation and rise above it. Or maybe it’s Daisy who messed it all up. Maybe the carelessness is to be blamed. But is Daisy a bad person? A good person? No, she’s simply a person. What’s truly dangerous is when a pretentious guy finds an opinionated love, when someone who deems himself to be the chosen one becomes engrossed in a love that may never reciprocate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps Gatsby’s dream was never quite pure. He bundled his quest for love with a childhood goal: that’s when his dream sublimated into something vibrant, something brave, and something beautiful. The tragedy is that though the dream might be possible, the love was a bubble destined to pop. His love was too dogged, too stubborn, too certain that what’s beautiful inevitably became tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of the waning illusion, Gatsby has lost his dream. His American Dream became Daisy, and he idly let himself be subjugated to Daisy’s standards. He became who he imagined she wanted him to be, but no matter how much he loved her (or thought he loved her), he never understood her. He understood her less than Tom, less than Nick. He was the fool who sought for that sickly, whimsical love more than he respected himself, more than he recognized his hard work, more than he understood his abilities. And in doing so, he’s lost himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s always had the opportunity to dominate the social ladder: there were many times when he could’ve reformed himself to be the modern Count of Monte Cristo, to become a better version of Jay, and to complete his social metamorphosis. But even though he did get rich, he never quite escaped from the dream of the boy who sailed the yacht. The unattainable dream that until death, he firmly believed he could accomplish. The dream of Daisy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Gatsby is great, &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; great. But he should’ve been more careful. He should’ve thought it through, his perseverance, his determination, his tireless pursuit, what it was all for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dreams-through-the-great-gatsby&quot;&gt;Dreams Through &lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So according to Fitzgerald, dreams may be illusions. Illusions that we might never quite grasp. They are the subconscious hints that we can be something we know we really can’t become. They are affirmations that we would always covet what we consciously know we can’t possess. People say his story is a tragedy, yet Gatsby never faltered in his chase for his dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the takeaway here is that the word “dream” carries the gravity of time. Dreams are meant to be left in the past. We don’t grow toward it, or for it. We grow out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt; is about youth, dream, and most importantly the courage to go after dreams even if the cost will be failure. No settling. No compromising. Just us persevering, beating on, boats against the current. But instead of being borne back into the past, we are heading for a future that may or may not be there, and I think that’s fearless too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Literature" /><category term="Gatsby" /><category term="Dream" /><summary type="html">Dreams are aspirations, yet less tangible. They are imaginations, yet more boundless. They are the instantaneous outburst of inner drive expressed in terms of outward hope. They represent all the hate about the present and all that will be marvelous in the future. They are the ultimate capacity for limitless creation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/hello/assets/images/Gatsby.jpg" /></entry></feed>